Guide to the Ruth Fulton Benedict Papers, 1857-1958
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES IV. WRITINGS OF RUTH BENEDICT
  - THE CHRYSANTHEMUM AND THE SWORD (1946)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 13, undated (Folder 50.16)
  - RACE: SCIENCE AND POLITICS (1940)
    - Race Bibliography, undated (Folder 51.1)
    - Race and Cultural Relations, undated (Folder 51.2)
    - Race: Science and Politics: Correspondence, undated (Folders 51.3-51.5)
    - Race: Science and Politics: Royalty Statements, undated (Folders 51.6-51.11)
    - Race: Extracts from Books, undated (Folder 51.12)
    - Montclair Civil Rights Audit, undated (Folder 51.13)
  - THE RACES OF MANKIND (1948)
    - The Races of Mankind -- Research Notes, undated (Folder 52.1)
    - The Races of Mankind -- Original Mss., undated (Folders 52.2-52.5)
    - The Races of Mankind -- Galley Proof, undated (Folder 52.6)
    - The Races of Mankind -- Original pamphlet annotated by RFB with pages from Italian edition, undated (Folder 52.7)
    - The Races of Mankind -- Press Release, undated (Folder 52.8)
    - Interview of RFB re: The Races of Mankind, undated (Folder 52.9)
    - The Races of Mankind -- The Nations United Against Fascism, undated (Folder 52.10)
    - Les Races du Genre Human, undated (Folder 52.11)
    - The Races of Mankind -- Clippings, undated (Folder 53.1-53.11)
  - UNPUBLISHED PROSE
    - American Melting Pot, 1941 Model (Folder 54.1)
    - The Bo-Cu Plant, by Edgar Stanhope [pseud. of RFB] [per RFB, "written with Stanley"; publ. in AAW], [1916] (Folder 54.2)
    - A Dream Biography of a Mountain Maidu, [undated.] (Folder 54.3)
    - The Family: Genus Americanus, [undated] (Folder 54.4)
    - Foreword to A Puerto Rican Town, [1948] (Folder 54.5)
    - The Functioning of the Dobuan Society, [undated] (Folder 54.6)
    - The Growth of Culture, [1947] (Folder 54.7)
    - The Growth of the Republic, [undated] (Folder 54.8)
    - Human Nature and the Anthropologist, [undated] (Folder 54.9)
    - If I Were a Negro, [undated] (Folder 54.10)
    - Japanese Origins: Official Versions Vs. Scientific, [undated] (Folder 54.11)
    - Memorandum to Conference on Science, Philosophy, and Religion, [circa 1943] (Folder 54.12)
    - A New York City Experiment in Home Making Courses in Wartime, [undated] (Folder 54.13)
    - North American Folklore, [undated] (Folder 54.14)
    - On the Role of the Faculty Instructor Concerning the Use of Living Subjects, [undated] (Folder 54.15)
    - Post War Experts, [undated] (Folder 54.16)
    - Racial Differences, [undated] (Folder 54.17)
    - The Study of Learned Cultural Behavior in Civilized Nations, [1947] (Folder 54.18)
    - [Unpublished Book Reviews], undated (Folder 54.19)
    - To Secure the Blessings of Liberty, [undated] (Folders 54.20-54.21)
    - Miscellaneous drafts and fragments, [undated] (Folders 55.1-55.12)
  - MARY WOLLSTONECRAFT
    - Notes - Mary Wollstonecraft, undated (Folder 56.1)
    - Notebook - Mary Wollstonecraft, undated (Folder 56.2)
    - Notebook - Mary Wollstonecraft, undated (Folder 56.3)
    - Notebook - A Vindication of the Rights of Woman, undated (Folder 56.4)
    - Mary Wollstonecraft, (TS, miscellaneous drafts) (Folder 56.5)
    - Mary Wollstonecraft, (MS, notes, drafts) (Folder 56.6)
    - Adventures in Womanhood, (TS) (Folder 56.7)
  - BOOK REVIEWS
    - Cawdor, by Robinson Jeffers [review signed by Anne Singleton; publ. in NY Herald Tribune Weekly Book Rev.], [1928] (Folder 57.1)
    - "The Chance for Life,", [undated] (Folder 57.2)
    - [Tihuanacu]: The Cradle of American Man, by I. Arthur Posnansky, [undated] (Folder 57.3)
    - Evolution and Ethics, by Sir Arthur Keith, 1947 (Folder 57.4)
    - Man for Himself: An Inquiry Into the Psychology of Ethics, by Erich Fromm, [1948] (Folder 57.5)
    - The Meeting of East and West, by F. S. C. Northrup [publ. in New Republic, v. 115], 1946 (Folder 57.6)
    - Men Before Adam, by Anne Terry White [publ. in NY Herald Tribune Weekly Book Rev., 12/27], 1942 (Folder 57.7)
    - Naven: A Survey of the Problems Suggested by a Composite Picture of a New Guinea Tribe, by Gregory Bateson [publ. in Review of Religion, vol. 2], [1937] (Folder 57.8)
    - The Neurotic Personality of Our Time, by Karen Horney [publ. in Journal of Soc. and Abnormal Psych., vol. 33], 1938 (Folder 57.9)
    - Prehistoric Cave Paintings, by Max Raphael [publ. in NY Herald Tribune Wkly. Book Rev., 1/27], 1946 (Folder 57.10)
    - Pueblo Indian Religion, by Elsie Clews Parsons [publ. in Review of Religion, vol. 4], 1940 (Folder 57.11)
    - Richer by Asia, by Edmond Taylor [publ. in Saturday Review of Literature, 7/26], 1947 (Folder 57.12)
    - The Road of Life and Death, by Paul Radin, 1947 (Folder 57.13)
    - Secret Societies: A Cultural Study of Fraternalism in the U.S., by Noel P. Gist, [1940] (Folder 57.14)
    - Social Anthropology, by Paul Radin, [1933] (Folder 57.15)
    - Social Reconstruction and the Christian Ethic, by F. W. Eggleston, [undated] (Folder 57.16)
    - The Study of Culture, by Bronislaw Malinowski, [undated] (Folder 57.17)
    - The Study of Man, by Ralph Linton, [1936] (Folder 57.18)
    - Sun Chief: The Autobiography of a Hopi Indian, ed. by Leo W. Simmons, [1942] (Folder 57.19)
    - Where the Two Came to Their Father: A Navaho War Ceremonial, by Joseph Campbell, [1943] (Folder 57.20)
  - SPEECHES AND LECTURES
    - Academic Freedom [fragment], [undated] (Folder 58.1)
    - America Converts to Peace, [1946] (Folder 58.2)
    - America's Racial Myths [lecture at Iowa], [undated] (Folder 58.3)
    - Anthropology and Mental Hygiene, [1932] (Folder 58.4)
    - Anthropology and Problems of Morale, [1940] (Folder 58.5)
    - Anthropology and Some Modern Alarmists [Anna Howard Shaw Lecture, no. V], Mar 1941 (Folder 58.6)
    - Anthropology and the Social Bases of Morale [Anna Howard Shaw Lecture, no. VI], Mar 1941 (Folder 58.7)
    - Can Cultural Patterns be Directed?, [undated] (Folder 58.8)
    - Comments on Juvenile Delinquency, [1930] (Folder 58.9)
    - Conference on Science, Philosophy, and Religion, [1942] (Folder 58.10)
    - Education and the Cultural Process, [undated] (Folder 58.11)
    - Educational Reconstruction in the Post-War World, [1941] (Folder 58.12)
    - "Enjoyment of Poetry," with Margaret Mead, WEVD radio program, 6 Apr 1958; (phonograph album) (Box 40)
    - The Facts About Race, [undated] (Folder 58.13)
    - Individual Behavior and the Social Order [Anna Howard Shaw Lecture, no. III], Feb 1941 (Folder 58.14)
    - Introduction for Malvina Hoffman, [undated] (Folder 58.15)
    - [Lecture, U. S. Dept. of Agriculture, Washington D.C.], [1938] (Folder 58.16)
    - Lectures on American Life series -- "Patterns of American Culture," Columbia University, 1948 (Folder 58.17)
    - A Message to the Intercultural Symposium of the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, [1946] (Folder 58.18)
    - People Live on Guadalcanal, [undated] (Folder 58.19)
    - The Problems of Anthropology [Anna Howard Shaw Lecture, no. I], Feb 1941 (Folder 58.20)
    - Property, [undated] (Folder 58.21)
    - The Psychology of Love, [1943] (Folder 58.22)
    - Race Prejudice in the United States [radio address, Washington, DC; publ. in AAW], [circa 1946] (Folder 58.23)
    - Remarks at Luncheon of Southern Conference, [undated] (Folder 58.24)
    - Remarks on Receiving Annual Achievement Award, AAUW, [1946] (Folder 58.25)
    - Speech at the Presentation of the Annual Achievement Award to Margaret Mead, [1940] (Folder 58.26)
    - The Study of Learned Cultural Behavior in Civilized Nations [Abstract written for Supper-Conference for Anthropologists], 1947 (Folder 58.27)
    - Superior Races: The World's Most Tragic Myth, [undated] (Folder 58.28)
    - [Untitled speech, given at Yale University], [1948] (Folder 58.29)
    - What Do We Mean by Democracy?, 1938 (Folder 58.30)
    - [Programs (2) of conferences at which RFB spoke], 1941-1942 (Folder 58.31)
- SERIES V. GRANT PROPOSALS, CONSULTING
  - Macy Foundation, undated (Folders 59.1-59.5)
  - Proposed Comparative Study of Polish and Russian Jews in the U.S., undated (Folder 59.6)
  - List of Grant Proposals and Field Trips, undated (Folder 59.7)
  - Funding Analysis for Columbia University Anthropology Department, undated (Folder 59.8)
  - Consulting, undated (Folder 59.9)
  - Grant Proposal: Agencies of White Contact, undated (Folder 59.10)
  - Proposal for a Training Center in the Culture and Character of European Peoples, undated (Folder 59.11)
  - A Plan for a Cultural Approach to the Problem of Inter-Group Tensions, undated (Folder 59.12)
  - Proposal for a Training Center in the Culture and Character of Contemporary Peoples, undated (Folder 60.1)
  - Grant Proposal: Studies in Acculturation, undated (Folder 60.2)
  - Grant Proposal: Project on Psychiatric Anthropology Submitted to the Rockefeller Foundation, Division of Medical Sciences, undated (Folder 60.3)
  - Rhodes-Livingstone Institute, undated (Folder 60.4)
  - Columbia University Department of Anthropology Project, undated (Folder 60.5)
  - Laboratory Field Trips to Primitive Cultures, undated (Folder 60.6)
  - Field Training and Research in Anthropology - Financial Statement, July 1932 - 25 Sep 25 1936 (Folder 60.7)
  - Report to Council for Research in Social Sciences, Columbia University, 1937 (Folder 60.8)
  - Project for the Study of Personality and Culture in Mexico, undated (Folder 60.9)
  - Application for funds for Research in Progress, 1931 (Folder 60.10)
  - Columbia University Approved Research, 1935 (Folder 60.11)
  - Social Science Research Council - Fellowship Application, undated (Folder 60.12)
  - Roster of Doctoral Exams, 1934 (Folder 60.13)
  - Preliminary Report on Anthropological Fieldwork, 1927 (Folder 60.14)
  - Grant Application - Mythology of the Zuñi Indians, undated (Folder 60.15)
  - Project for Ethnological Work in Brazil (Columbia University), undated (Folder 60.16)
  - Project for Anthropological Work in Pará, undated (Folder 60.17)
  - Sourcebook on Intercultural Education, undated (Folder 60.18)
  - Proposal for the Cataloguing of the Columbia University Art Collections, undated (Folder 60.19)
  - 1935 Research, etc., undated (Folder 60.20)
- SERIES VI. TEACHING AND LECTURE NOTES
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Anthropology 101, undated (Folder 61.1)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Anthropology 102, Race and Culture, undated (Folder 61.2)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Anthropology 161, Contemporary Problems, undated (Folder 61.3)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Anthropology Seminar, 1930-1931 (Folder 61.4)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Seminar, undated (Folder 61.5)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, American Indian, undated (Folder 61.6)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Animism, undated (Folder 61.7)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Australia, undated (Folders 61.8-61.11)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Child Rearing, undated (Folder 62.1)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Crow, undated (Folder 62.2)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Folklore, undated (Folder 62.3)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Kinship, undated (Folder 62.4)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Kinship Schedules, undated (Folder 62.5)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Linguistic Stocks, undated (Folder 62.6)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Melanesia, undated (Folders 62.7-62.10)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Mythology, undated (Folder 62.11)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Mythology, undated (BOX 63)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Mythology, undated (BOX 64)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Mythology, undated (Folder 65.1)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Mythology (Anthropology 107), undated (Folder 65.2)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Religion, undated (Folders 65.3-65.11)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Social Organization, undated (Folder 65.12)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Social Organization, undated (Folder 65.13)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Social Organization, undated (Folders 66.1-66.5)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Spanish Tales, undated (Folder 66.6)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, undated (Folder 66.7)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Extracts from Books, undated (Folder 66.8)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Extracts from Books, undated (Folder 66.9)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Field Materials, undated (Folder 66.10)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Lecture and Projects, undated (Folder 66.11)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Miscellaneous, undated (Folder 67.1)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Miscellaneous, undated (Folder 67.2)
  - Teaching and Lecture Notes, Notebooks, undated (Folder 67.3)
  - Miscellaneous Field Notes ("Sample field notebook - [Marie Eichelberger] '54"), undated (Folder 67.4)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Folder 67.5)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Folder 67.6)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, South America, undated (Folder 67.7)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, South America, undated (BOX 68)
  - Miscellaneous Reading Notes, undated (Folder 67.8)
  - Miscellaneous Research Projects, undated (Folder 67.9)
  - Notes, Psychology of Faith Group, undated (Folder 67.10)
  - [Indexed Note Cards on Various Topics], undated (BOX 69)
- SERIES VII. STUDENT PAPERS AND MISCELLANEOUS STUDENT REPORTS
  - Botkin, B. A.: A Collection of Oklahoma Texts and Tunes, pt. 2, undated (Folder 70.1)
  - Brenner, Anita: Notes for a Study of the Mexican Nahual, undated (Folder 70.2)
  - Cantine, H. R., jr.: The Folklore of the Kiwai Papuans, undated (Folder 70.3)
  - Diehl, Walter: Staden and Métraux on the Tupinamba, undated (Folder 70.4)
  - Geismar, David: North American Indian Mythology (for Anthro. 114), undated (Folder 70.5)
  - Gibel, Fela: [Course Paper on Contemporary Problems] (for Anthro. 161), undated (Folder 70.6)
  - Grace, Harry A.: Some Hypotheses on the Relationship Between the Culture and the Screen Personality (for Anthro. 121), undated (Folder 70.7)
  - Greenwall, H. P.: Abstracts of Stories from Die Nayarit Expedition by Preuss (for Anthro. 204), undated (Folder 70.8)
  - Hall, Mildred: The Story of the Sun Snarer, undated (Folder 70.9)
  - Hallowell, Dorothy Kern: The Problem of Racial Psychology (for Graduate Seminar), undated (Folder 70.10)
  - Halseth, Odd S.: [Student Study: Plans and Accomplishments], undated (Folder 70.11)
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson: Big Turtle's War Party (for Anthro. 114), undated (Folder 70.12)
  - Hoffman, Dan G.: Pictorial Art in Three Cultures (for Anthro. 101), undated (Folder 71.1)
  - Holzer (Harold) Case History - Delinquency, undated (Folder 71.2)
  - Jones, Yvonne: The People of Dobu, undated (Folder 71.3)
  - Keller, Thelma C.: The Deserted Children (for Anthro. 114), undated (Folder 71.4)
  - Migration Tales, undated (Folder 71.5)
  - Milk Drinking Habits Among Young People: A psychological study made cooperatively by the Milk Research Council and the University of Newark Research Center, undated (Folder 71.6)
  - Siegel, Morris: Effects of Contact on the Form of the Family in a Guatemalan Village, undated (Folder 71.7)
  - Study of Urban Women, undated (Folder 71.8)
  - Woodward, Patricia: Summary of Interviews on German Culture, undated (Folder 71.9)
  - Student Field Trips, undated (Folder 71.10)
  - Student Grade Sheets, undated (Folder 71.11)
  - Student Notes to Ruth Benedict, undated (Folder 71.12)
- SERIES VIII. MISCELLANEOUS PROSE AND POETRY BY OTHERS
  - Poetry of Léonie Adams sent to Ruth Benedict, undated (Folder 72.1)
  - Miscellaneous poetry by others, undated (Folder 72.2)
  - Miscellaneous prose by others, undated (Folder 72.3)
- SERIES IX. BIBLIOGRAPHY
  - Bibliography: Africa, undated (Folder 73.1)
  - Bibliography: American Indian, undated (Folder 73.2)
  - Bibliography: The American School of the Air (CBS), undated (Folder 73.3)
  - Bibliography: Anthropology I, undated (Folder 73.4)
  - Bibliography: Anthropology II, undated (Folder 73.5)
  - Bibliography: Archaeology and Ethnology, undated (Folder 73.6)
  - Bibliography: Bernice P. Bishop Museum Publications, undated (Folder 73.7)
  - Bibliography: Boas, undated (Folder 73.8-10)
  - Bibliography: Books about the Negro, undated (Folder 73.11)
  - Bibliography: Columbia University Contributions to Anthropology, undated (Folder 73.12)
  - Bibliography: Cultural Anthropology, undated (Folder 73.13)
  - Bibliography: Cultural Anthropology, undated (Folder 73.14)
  - Bibliography: Cultural Dynamics, undated (Folder 73.15)
  - Bibliography: Culture and Personality, undated (Folder 73.16)
  - Bibliography: The Dr. Raymond Pearl Library, undated (Folder 73.17)
  - Bibliography: The Eskimo, undated (Folder 73.18)
  - Bibliography: Farther India, undated (Folder 74.1)
  - Bibliography: Fiction, undated (Folder 74.2)
  - Bibliography: Government, undated (Folder 74.3)
  - Bibliography: Guide to Undergraduate Students, undated (Folder 74.4)
  - Bibliography: Interamerican Training Projects, undated (Folder 74.5)
  - Bibliography: The Literature of the Native Administration, undated (Folder 74.6)
  - Bibliography: Man and the Supernatural, undated (Folder 74.7)
  - Bibliography: Miscellaneous, undated (Folder 74.8)
  - Bibliography: New York State Library, undated (Folder 74.9)
  - Bibliography: Philippines, undated (Folder 74.10)
  - Bibliography: Polynesia, undated (Folder 74.11)
  - Bibliography: Religion, undated (Folder 74.12)
  - Bibliography: Ruth Benedict's Published Works, undated (Folder 74.13)
  - Bibliography: Selected Ethnographic Bibliography of the Plains, undated (Folder 74.14)
  - Bibliography: Southeast Asia, undated (Folder 74.15)
  - Bibliography: Syllabus and Instructions for Anthropology 1A, 1B, undated (Folder 74.16)
  - [Unpublished Bibliography], undated (Folder 74.17)
- SERIES X. GENERAL SUBJECT FILES
  - General Subject Files: Africa, undated (Folder 75.1)
  - General Subject Files: African Americans, undated (Folder 75.2)
  - General Subject Files: Benedict (Articles about), undated (Folder 75.3)
  - General Subject Files: Benedict (Mention of RFB), undated (Folder 75.4)
  - General Subject Files: Benedict articles and reprints, undated (Folder 75.5)
  - General Subject Files: Benedict articles and reprints, undated (Folder 75.6)
  - General Subject Files: Benedict book reviews, undated (Folder 75.7)
  - General Subject Files: Benedict - Reviews of Her Books, undated (Folder 75.8)
  - General Subject Files: Columbia University President, Nicholas Murray Butler, undated (Folder 75.9)
  - General Subject Files: East and West Association, undated (Folder 75.10)
  - General Subject Files: Education, undated (Folder 75.11)
  - General Subject Files: Holland, undated (Folder 76.1)
  - General Subject Files: In Henry's Backyard, undated (Folder 76.2)
  - General Subject Files: Italy, undated (Folder 76.3)
  - General Subject Files: Jews, undated (Folder 76.4)
  - General Subject Files: Miscellaneous, undated (Folder 76.5)
  - General Subject Files: Native Americans, undated (Folder 76.6)
  - General Subject Files: Native Americans, undated (Folder 76.7)
  - General Subject Files: Public Works, undated (Folder 77.1)
  - General Subject Files: Racism and Prejudice, undated (Folder 77.2)
  - General Subject Files: Rumania, undated (Folder 77.3)
  - General Subject Files: Russia, undated (Folder 77.4)
  - General Subject Files: Science and Technology, undated (Folder 77.5)
  - General Subject Files: South America, undated (Folder 77.6)
  - General Subject Files: Southwest, undated (Folder 77.7)
  - General Subject Files: Spain, undated (Folder 77.8)
  - General Subject Files: Turkish Students, undated (Folder 77.9)
  - General Subject Files: World War II, undated (Folder 77.10)
  - General Subject Files: World War II -- Commentary, undated (Folder 77.11)
  - General Subject Files: Yugoslavia, undated (Folder 77.12)
  - General Subject Files: Miscellaneous Clippings, undated (Folders 78.1-78.6)
- SERIES XI. NATIVE AMERICAN SUBJECT FILES, Some of this material is available online at Alexander Street Press's Anthropology Commons.
  - GENERAL
    - Mescalero Trip: Accounts, undated (Folder 79.1)
    - Mescalero Trip: Applications, undated (Folder 79.2)
    - Mescalero Trip: Clippings re: Henrietta Schmerler, 1931 (Folder 79.3)
    - Mescalero Trip: Correspondence: Regina Flannery, 1932 (Folder 79.4)
    - Mescalero Trip: Correspondence: Paul Frank, 1931 (Folder 79.5)
    - Mescalero Trip: Correspondence: John Gillen, 1932 (Folder 79.6)
    - Mescalero Trip: Correspondence: Jesse Nussbaum, 1931 (Folder 79.7)
    - Mescalero Trip: Correspondence: Jesse Nussbaum, 1931-1932 (Folder 79.8)
    - Mescalero Trip: Correspondence: Morris Oppler [for other Oppler correspondence, see folders 32.12-32.13], 1931-1933 (Folder 79.9)
    - Mescalero Trip: Correspondence: Morris Oppler [for other Oppler correspondence, see folders 32.12-32.13], 1933 (Folder 79.10)
    - Mescalero Trip: Correspondence: Edward Sapir, 1931 (Folder 79.11)
    - Mescalero Trip: Correspondence re: Henrietta Schmerler, 1931-1932 (Folder 79.12)
    - Mescalero Trip: Correspondence re: Students, 1931 (Folder 79.13)
    - Mescalero Trip: Correspondence: Sol Tax [for other Tax correspondence, see folder 34.6], 1932 (Folder 79.14)
    - Mescalero Trip: Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Folder 79.15)
    - Pima Mythology - Notebook, undated (Folder 80.1)
    - Pima Mythology - Notebook, undated (Folder 80.2)
    - Pima Mythology - Notes, undated (Folders 80.3-80.5)
    - Pima Mythology - Song Transcriptions, Notes, undated (Folder 80.6)
    - Pima Mythology - Song Transcriptions, undated (Folder 80.7)
    - Pima Mythology - Song Transcriptions, undated (Folder 80.8)
    - Pima Mythology - Bluebird and Coyote Try To Make Themselves Blue, undated (Folder 80.9)
    - Pima Mythology - Bungling Host/The Girl Who Would Not Marry, undated (Folder 80.10)
    - Pima Mythology - Corn Woman, undated (Folder 80.11)
    - Pima Mythology - Coyote and the Turkeys/The Benefactors, undated (Folder 80.12)
    - Pima Mythology - Coyote Is Pursued By a Lion/The Crows Get New Feathers, undated (Folder 80.13)
    - Pima Mythology - Coyote Marries the Hunter's Wives, undated (Folder 80.14)
    - Pima Mythology - Coyotes Make War Against the Sun, undated (Folder 80.15)
    - Pima Mythology - Creation, undated (Folder 80.16)
    - Pima Mythology - Deer Planter, undated (Folder 80.17)
    - Pima Mythology - Dove Makes Magic for a Race/The Survivors, undated (Folder 80.18)
    - Pima Mythology - The Dragonfly Asks Tobacco to Return, undated (Folder 80.19)
    - Pima Mythology - Eagle Hawk Man, undated (Folder 80.20)
    - Pima Mythology - The Feud, undated (Folder 80.21)
    - Pima Mythology - The Feud of the Coyote Brothers, undated (Folder 80.22)
    - Pima Mythology - Figures of Speech Among the Pima, undated (Folder 80.23)
    - Pima Mythology - Frog and Water/The Origin of Tobacco, undated (Folder 80.24)
    - Pima Mythology - The Giant Cactus/The Mesquite Tree, undated (Folder 80.25)
    - Pima Mythology - Haak, undated (Folder 81.1)
    - Pima Mythology - Harvest Ceremony, undated (Folder 81.2)
    - Pima Mythology - Koolhaa, undated (Folder 81.3)
    - Pima Mythology - Man Eagle, undated (Folder 81.4)
    - Pima Mythology - Navictu, undated (Folder 81.5)
    - Pima Mythology - Old Woman's Grandson Rescues His Mother from the Apache, undated (Folder 81.6)
    - Pima Mythology - The Orphan Boy, undated (Folder 81.7)
    - Pima Mythology - Rain Ritual, undated (Folder 81.8)
    - Pima Mythology - Remarks to Pima Speeches, undated (Folder 81.9)
    - Pima Mythology - Ritual for the First Water Allowed the Slayer in the Purification Rites, undated (Folder 81.10)
    - Pima Mythology - Songs of the Trading of the Turquoise Chain, undated (Folder 81.11)
    - Pima Mythology - The Sons of Naasa, undated (Folder 81.12)
    - Pima Mythology - The Sons of Rain, undated (Folder 81.13)
    - Pima Mythology - The Tsaidjuukam, undated (Folder 81.14)